- Previously on "Gotham"...
- You left me the virus.
You've got two options.
You can take the virus
and find the strength
and get out of there. Or...
you can make that coffin
your permanent home.
Fish?
Why are you here?
- I was alive.
- Good-bye, Fish!
Then I was dead.
Let's try subject 13, shall we?
And then, I was alive.
Impossible.
Nothing...
is impossible.
Things are looking up.
My little Penguin and I will be leaving.
This detonator will trigger the bomb.
Thousands will be
infected with the virus.
Let Gotham fall so you may rise.
I won't have him
turn you into a murderer.
No. You will press it!
When you're ready, come and find me.
Oh, my.
What's happening out there?
My money, my savings.
- My savings.
- Excuse me, what?
My-my money, my savings.
I want my money, my savings.
- What's your account number?
- My whole life.
My money, my savings.
I want my savings.
- My money, my savings.
- Uh, this account was closed
- due to unpaid fees.
- No, my money,
my savings, my life.
- You have no money.
- Everything.
The account is closed.
Give me my money now!
Oh, God. Um, security?
Hey, what are you...
My money, my savings.
Now!
Hey, I'm paying for this.
Get out!
Come here! Come back!
Buy our cookies!
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
Move on.
Killer...
killer...
you're a killer.
Killer...
Killer!
Jim?
You okay?
Fine.
I'm fine, Harvey.
Listen, I hate to do this to you, pal.
But I'm gonna have to ask for your gun.
This virus is tearing the city apart.
You need me. I can control this.
That's why I'm not
asking for your badge.
Some of the guys are talking.
These cops are gonna be watching you
for the smallest sign.
Okay? And if you've got a gun,
they'll be double jumpy.
It's for your own protection.
Any word on Lee?
Nada. What happened after the bombing?
A mob of infected
swarmed the clock tower.
- She disappeared in the chaos.
- I don't get it.
She went through all that effort
to get you infected with
the virus and she just bolts?
She saw I was fighting it.
She's waiting for me to give over to it.
Prove her wrong.
Where's Bruce?
Detective Gordon.
Alfred.
Has he said anything?
No, no, he just sits there staring.
I need to talk to him, Harvey.
We sure that's not the clone?
No, that's Bruce.
God knows what those
bastards done to him,
but he's only brainwashed.
Are you really the best
person to talk to him?
I mean, from what you said, you
killed his mentor or something.
He might be a bit peeved.
Listen, whatever they did to him,
that is Bruce Wayne in there.
That boy is stronger than
you can possibly imagine.
I just need to make him remember...
who he is.
As long as he doesn't
leave the precinct.
Harvey, something you need to see.
An antidote?
Lucius, I could kiss your face.
Before you do that, I don't
actually have the formula.
But there is an antidote?
That's what you're saying?
I was going through the papers
you recovered from
the Owl leader's house.
They suggest that while
Strange was working
to weaponize the Tetch virus,
he was also working
on a parallel project,
tailoring different antiviral
agents to his own ends.
Strange was designing an antidote.
That makes sense.
The Court was careful
to protect its own.
They would want a safeguard.
We need to talk to Strange.
Is he still here or has he been moved?
Uh, well, when you were
buried in the coffin
and the city was
about to be virus-bombed,
some decisions had to be made.
Harvey...
I told Alfred to question Strange.
In exchange for him telling us
where the bombing was
gonna go down, Alfred
let Strange walk. Yes,
I'm blaming it on the butler.
All right. Strange is a weasel.
He'd try to get as far away
from this as possible.
Union Station is shut down.
Downtown train station's our best bet.
Okay. Wait up.
Harvey?
Lucius, I know what
you're gonna say, all right?
He can handle this.
Hell, Barnes had the virus
for weeks before anyone knew.
What I was going to say:
from all I see here,
Strange's virus is an accelerated
version of the Tetch virus.
Why do you think people
are reacting so quickly?
Gordon isn't going to be able
to fight this for long.
Well, we'll just have to
wait and see, huh?
You keep working on that antidote.
One second, one second,
one ticket at a time.
Go get what's her name.
Sir, excuse me!
Ooh.
Excuse me.
Oh, no.
I think you mean, "Hello, Fish.
I miss you."
And don't worry, sweetheart.
The fun has just begun.
"As the flames of henism
licked the very foundation
of its society..."
"...Nero played and sang
'The Destruction of Troy.'"
I will say this about the Court of Owls:
they have style.
Not to mention they've handed us
the perfect opportunity.
For what?
The city is in total disarray.
What better time to consolidate power?
Barbara,
I've told you again and again,
I have no interest in running Gotham.
- I only want...
- To kill Penguin. Yes.
I got it the first billion times.
And where is he now? Oh!
That's right, with Fish Mooney.
So we find her.
And then what? You blast through
her army of goons
until you get to Oswald?
You're gonna need muscle, honey.
Which you provide.
Oh, so you expect my help?
But when I need yours,
to take advantage of an
opportunity of a lifetime...
...nothing.
Baby.
Listen, all I ask
is that you use this beautiful
big brain of yours
to help me, finally,
get this city under my thumb.
And afterwards,
I will help you
pry Penguin away from Fish.
Deal?
I will give you a day.
I thought we were friends.
When the Court of Owls calls,
o-one does not refuse.
Still, I'm not upset.
I knew when your old
masters summoned you,
it was to cook up some horror,
and here's the thing:
I need horror.
They're responsible
for all of this, aren't they?
At the behest of the Court,
I weaponized a virus
that releases a person's darkest urges.
Thousands have been infected.
So where is this virus?
I know there's more.
It has all been used. Please, I must go.
Don't. You will give me the virus,
you will make me the army you promised,
you will do everything I say
until this city
is in the palm of my hand.
Are we clear?
Yes, madam.
Sorry, folks, this exit's off...
I'll look around for the station cop,
see if he found Strange.
Hello?
Oh, geez. He's right here.
- This is Gordon.
- Hi, Jim.
I was just checking in,
seeing how you're feeling.
Crazy day, huh?
Lee, where are you?
Somewhere very familiar to you.
I know how you're feeling.
All that blood rushing
through your veins,
your heart beating
faster and faster.
Listen to me,
you need to turn yourself in;
it's not safe.
The infected are being killed
all over the city.
Wow, you're really fighting this, huh?
You know, you don't have to.
The cage is finally open, Jim.
You're free.
- No.
- I thought you loved me.
I thought you wanted us to be together.
Not like this.
Well...
...this is the only way, Jim.
Just listen to the whispers.
Killer.
They'll lead you to me,
tell you who you are.
Killer.
That's not who I am.
I wonder what they're saying.
That you like hurting people,
killing people?
Killer.
See how well I know you, Jim.
Now I'm gonna go have some fun.
We'll catch up soon.
Promise.
Killer... killer...
you're a killer.
Jim! Jim.
Someone spotted Strange.
Just don't shoot any
innocent bystanders.
Or me. Especially me.
- GCPD!
- Don't move!
Fish?
What a surprise.
My goodness, Harvey, you look awful.
It's good to see you, too.
We just want Strange. You can walk away.
Yeah. Uh, no.
Fish, I know in your own
sick way, you love this city,
and Gotham is bleeding to death.
We need this dirtbag to fix it.
Enough talking. Hand him over.
He has it.
It's in his eyes.
He has the virus.
Really?
So tell me, James,
what's it feel like?
Like it's taking all my willpower...
not to kill you.
Ooh, my.
Harvey, when you say Hugo
here can save the city,
does that mean there's a...
cure for this virus?
Fish, I swear to God,
if you don't step back,
I will shoot you and
these two nimrods right here,
right now!
Hugo, is it true
that you're the only one
that can stop this madness?
Mm-hmm.
Obviously, I can't give him up now.
Fine, you had your chance.
Oh.
Did you really think that I
would come without backup?
- You're a killer.
- Jim,
- dial it down, buddy.
- Victor,
looks like our little
Detective Gordon is overheating.
Perhaps you should cool him off.
Both of them.
Marvelous.
Just marvelous.
There he is,
the real James Gordon.
Nice to meet you, at last.
There we go, Master Bruce.
Two lumps, just how you like it.
You hungry, mate?
Can I whip you up a sandwich?
Anyway, if all goes well,
we should be able to
head back to Wayne Manor tomorrow.
Although, I was thinking
that we could go abroad.
We could go to Switzerland.
I mean, we used to go with your
mum and dad this time of year.
Stop it.
Your attempts to elicit
an emotional response
by reminding me of shared memories
is clumsy and pathetic.
The last memory I have is of
you killing the best friend
and teacher I ever had.
You mean that old geezer that...
kidnapped you, poisoned your mind,
then tried to turn you
into a mass murderer.
Let me tell you something, Master Bruce:
that man lied to you.
Him and his bloody Court of Owls,
they tried to use you,
they tried to manipulate you.
You say he was a liar.
How?
By taking away the pain
I've carried for years?
By giving me revenge against the people
who killed my mother and father?
That's more than you ever did.
Anyway, the Court of Owls
does not matter.
They merely paved the way
for the one who is to come.
What do you mean?
Who-who's coming?
You'll see.
- I should cook him.
- They want him alive.
So I'll just cook part of him.
Oh, no, my dear.
- Let's be calm.
- You don't have that kind of control.
And you do?
In my hands,
this flamethrower is a scalpel.
Fine.
We each take a foot.
Whoever goes above the ankle loses.
You're on.
No. N-No. Stop!
Ms. Mooney! Ms. Mooney!
Mooney's busy.
I'm here now.
Mmm.
Also, I think your children
are angry with you.
- Mr. Cobblepot.
- It's understandable.
You made them what they are,
then abandoned them.
You are working with Ms. Mooney?
We're partners.
But you tried to kill her.
And she forgave me.
I know. Surprised me, too.
But, Mooney is not the old Mooney.
She has evolved.
And she has a vision for Gotham.
She sees a city where
people like myself,
Victor, Bridgit... freaks...
are in charge.
And you are gonna help us achieve that.
- I can't.
- Wrong, Professor!
This virus is tearing Gotham apart.
That makes your antidote the
most valuable thing in the city.
We could demand half of Gotham
and the city council
deliver it to us on a platter.
So, I'm going to ask you once,
where is it?
If I tell you where the antidote is,
I have nothing.
I can't.
You can torture me all you want.
Okay.
What?
You know, when I was in Arkham,
I was tortured daily.
Oh. Well, that was therapy, Oswald.
Therapy.
And that device you used
to administer the therapy,
remember that?
It gave the sensation
that your head was being torn open
so that hot lava could be poured
directly into your brain.
Afterwards,
just thinking of it
would make me physically ill.
So, naturally, I had to have it.
- Oh!
- One moment, Oswald.
No! All right, all right!
I'll-I'll tell you anything
you need to know.
- I'll tell you where the antidote is.
- I know.
But not just yet, 'kay?
What?
They're not answering at the precinct.
They must be overwhelmed.
Well, we're not shooting our way out.
Killer.
Jim, take it easy.
Someone will come!
Yeah, and by then,
Mooney will have gotten Strange
to give her the antidote!
We're running out of time!
Killer.
Killer. Killer.
Killer!
I knew you could do it.
Come on, Jim! Fight it!
Fight the damn virus!
Not my car. That's my car!
Let me drive.
Alvarez, spread the word,
Mayor James has called in
the National Guard.
We don't want any soldiers
getting shot by mistake.
Leave me alone.
The hell's wrong with you?
Alvarez, I'm talking to you.
I said leave me alone!
So, I will ask you again.
Who's coming?
I mean, I thought
the man that I dispatched
at Wayne Enterprises was the
leader of the Court of Owls.
I want you to leave.
Yeah, well, that ain't
gonna happen, is it, mate?
You can't get rid of me that easy.
You have to remember
who you are.
I know who I am. I have a destiny.
Now, you listen to me.
That man that wanted you
to detonate that bomb...
whatever he promised you...
freedom from pain, power... none of it,
none of it was real.
I want you to remember what is real.
I know what's real!
I got vengeance for my parents' murder.
That's real!
No.
No, that's not real.
What's real
is every time that you were sick
when you were a kid...
your mum used to sit up
with you all night
and read to you till you
fell asleep. That's real.
Or when you were seven and you
took your silly rowing boat out
and you got lost in that storm,
and me and your dad were out,
shouting and screaming,
losing our minds.
And when your dad found you,
how he cried.
That's real.
Yes...
your parents died in that alley
three years ago
and maybe that man took away
the pain of that night.
But there is no life,
there is no love without pain.
He could not touch the love
that your mom and dad gave you,
that you still have it in you,
that you still have in here.
The same love that I have for you.
I love you, Master Bruce.
I would do anything for you.
I would die for you.
You must...
find that love again.
Come back to me, Master Bruce.
Thank you very much.
No problem.
Excuse me.
Oh, bloody hell.
What I'm saying is
if Penguin and Fish have hooked up,
things are gonna get
real bad, real fast.
- You want to run?
- No.
I'm saying maybe she takes care
of Barbara and Nygma for us.
I mean, we can even help things along.
Send word to Fish
about where Babs is weak.
This is our shot.
I'm not ready.
What the hell is she doing here?
One whiskey. Here you go.
Well, this is a strange day.
Never thought I'd see you in here.
Had some time to kill
while my ex sees the light.
Figured I'd have a little fun.
Where's Babs?
- What do you want with her?
- None of your business, errand boy.
I'm sorry, what did you call me?
I'm sorry, you're not an errand boy.
You're more of a shoeshine boy.
They should give you a little stand
in the front, cute little hat.
- That's more your speed.
- Right. Out.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Oh...
You've got the virus.
Wow, you're not as dumb as I've heard.
Are there any other glaringly
obvious remarks you'd like to make?
How about I cut your lungs out
and show them to you?
Wow, that's incredibly vivid.
I'd like to see you try it.
But I'm here for your boss,
the crazy blonde.
- She's not my boss.
- Uh-huh.
I may have a virus making me
freakishly strong and mildly insane,
but even I know that you were
a sidekick to your brother
and you're a sidekick to Barbara.
So, can you send her a message for me?
Would you?
Your boss...
...tell her next time I see her,
I'm gonna rip her head
right off her body.
Bye now.
- God...
- What, you need help?
It's all criminal activity.
Go back inside.
- Gotham curfew.
- Got him.
Shut down.
All individuals must remain indoors.
Any activity outdoors
will be considered criminal activity.
Clear here.
Let's go, let's go. Clear out.
Remain indoors.
He's following directions or something.
I've got to find out
who's controlling him,
who's brainwashed him.
And then what?
I'm gonna kill the bastard.
You two wait here.
Professor, if this is a trap,
you will soon find yourself hanging
- with the rest of the meat.
- It's no trap.
I tested earlier versions of the virus
and the antidote on livestock.
I made sure to set aside
a successful batch.
This place gives me the creeps.
I like it.
It's concentrated.
Once you dilute it,
there is enough here to cure
every infected person in Gotham.
Hmm.
Oswald,
you and I will rule this city together.
Yes.
But first, I have to kill Ed Nygma.
He has to die.
Oh, he will.
And all those who try
to stand in our way.
What's this?
Who's there?
Show yourself.
Who are they?
Don't look at me, I don't know.
Really? That's all you've got?
Hand over the antidote now.
I want the Strike Force and
all available units there now.
I'm on my way.
Reports of an ice storm and fireball
at an East Side slaughterhouse.
- Do you think maybe...
- Just drive the damn car.
Sweet mother mercy.
Killer.
You damn fool.
Fish!
Oswald.
It's okay. It's-it's o...
We can, we can get you some help.
No, no, no.
I've done this enough times
to know I'm finished.
No. D-Do not say that.
- We-we will get you help.
- Listen to me.
Listen to me.
Make this city yours...
...or you burn it to the ground.
People call me a monster.
You, Jim Gordon,
you're the mons...
You're right. I am a monster.
- GCPD!
- Arrest them!
All of them!
Strange...
You better tell me that you
can make more of that antidote.
Yes, yes.
I just need one thing.
How's it hanging?
You sure about this?
According to my sources,
Fish Mooney and the GCPD
are scrambling to recover
the antidote to this virus.
But Fish is dead.
And Hugo Strange,
who designed the antidote,
is setting up a lab in the GCPD,
but they are missing one
very, very important element.
So, yes, I am sure that this bozo
is the key to controlling Gotham.
Are you my saviors?
Are you the ones to set me free?
Not exactly.
Let's make Gotham beg.
Seek out the Yuyan building.
Find the demon's head.
Fulfill your destiny.
Right. Find Bullock,
let him know where we are.
I'm gonna follow Bruce.
I wouldn't touch that, Bruce.
You know who I am?
Who do you think told
the Sensei to send you here?
He's dead.
He was murdered.
He died.
But he completed his task.
The Court of Owls is destroyed,
Gotham burns, and you...
are here.
He told me to complete my training,
to find the demon's head.
You already have, Bruce.
I'm the one you seek.
I'm the demon's head.
I am Ra's al Ghul.
Why have you come to me, Bruce?
The Sensei told me to seek you out.
That you would complete my training.
And did the Sensei tell you
who I am, what I seek?
I know you are not a part
of the Court of Owls,
that you only used them.
But I don't know why.
Then know that I have been alive
more years than you can imagine.
That I have seen and done things
that would shake the core
of everything you believe.
That I'm thought to be a demon...
a saint...
a ghost.
But for all my years, all my travels,
there is one thing
that I have never found:
a true heir.
But I need to know if you're ready.
I am.
The Sensei trained me.
Are you?
He set you a task.
He asked you to be the one
that released the virus
that now envelops this city.
You failed.
I would have. But...
but Alfred, he distracted me.
I know.
And that's why I'm gonna
give you another chance
to complete your journey.
Oh, don't look so surprised,
Master Bruce.
I told you you couldn't
get rid of me that easy.
Just got a bit sloppy.
Got a bit of ring rust.
Let these little ninja monkeys
get one over on me.
You all right, mate?
What you come as?
Enough.
This man...
is your past, Bruce.
Now, embrace your future.
Kill him.
Join me.
Fulfill your destiny.
He's wrong.
Master Bruce,
there's no other way to put it.
He's wrong.
Your destiny is to be Bruce Wayne.
And one day, you're gonna remember that.
And you're gonna remember
how much I love you.
I remember the first time
your mum and dad brought you home.
They were so exhausted.
And they gave you to me.
This tiny, defenseless little creature.
And they said, "Look after him,"
and I said, "Sure."
And I scooped you up in my arms,
and I held you,
and you opened your eyes...
...and you looked at me.
And at that moment, I decided
that I would do anything for you.
Anything.
So, if this is what you need to do,
Master Bruce, you crack on.
You do it.
Join me.
Bruce.
Alfred. Alfred!
Alfred!
Alfred, no.
Alfred.
You've broken through your conditioning.
Impressive.
You don't control me anymore!
I will never be your heir!
On the contrary.
Your strength only confirms
what the prophecy has foretold.
An heir to serve
as my knight in the darkness.
I will never
follow you!
You made me kill Alfred!
Use the waters, Bruce.
Our time will come.
Bruce.
Alfred. Alfred. Alfred.
A citywide lockdown
continues to remain in effect,
with Gotham officials urging people
to stay inside their homes, as
thousands of infected citizens
continue their rampage through the city.
Local law enforcement is thus far...
Lee.
Where are you?
Why? You miss me?
- The city's not safe.
- Mm.
Well, that's why I'm packing a bag.
What are you talking about?
I'm leaving Gotham.
And I want you to come with me.
I'll take your silence
as a yes?
Lee, you can't leave.
There are checkpoints all over the city.
Who are you trying to convince, Jim?
I can hear it in your voice:
you want this
as much as I do.
We can finally be together,
without judgment
or secrets or jealousy.
After everything we've been through,
don't we deserve that?
I am leaving on the afternoon train.
And I want you with me.
But I want the real you.
So tell me you'll stop fighting it.
Tell me I won't lose you again.
Tell me you'll be there.
I'll be there.
Hey, Jim.
Where are we with Tetch?
Barbara and Nygma
gave the mayor's office
a list of demands...
friend snuck me a copy.
They also threatened to kill Tetch
if we tried to take him back by force.
Half of these would bankrupt the city.
The alternative being there's
no city left to bankrupt.
We don't have any cards to play,
partner. We got no moves.
Yes, we do.
Him.
Penguin?
This entire list is Barbara's,
except for him.
Penguin is the only thing
Nygma cares about.
- The question is: how much?
- No way.
There is no way we're turning him over.
- Why not?
- Because we don't have the authority
to broker some kind of secret
deal behind the city's back.
Much less one that leads to
the imminent death of its former mayor.
Nygma would betray Barbara
and hand over Tetch
if given half the chance.
I need to save Lee!
I don't have much time, Harvey.
It's now or never.
You know, one of these days,
I'm gonna say "never."
Hello?
Nygma, it's Gordon.
I'm calling with a proposition.
Can you talk?
I can listen.
We need to kill her.
How much longer are we gonna wait?
Come on.
Nygma chopped off your hand.
He almost killed me.
And now Barbara's partners with him?
That's the mother of all insults.
The city is gonna pay us
a lot of money to get Tetch back.
We need to let that play out
before we do anything rash.
I know you two are close.
But whatever you had,
she treats you like dirt now.
She treats us both like
dirt, and you know it.
She doesn't deserve your loyalty.
What are you two whispering about?
Nothing. Any word from city hall?
Trust me, we're about to own this town.
Parts of it quite literally.
Where's Ed?
He was just here a minute ago.
Tetch?!
Nygma!
How could you let this happen?
Us? You're the one that trusted him.
I asked you to do one thing:
watch a man tied to a chair!
You idiots can't even do that!
- Where are we going?
- Shut up.
Look, I'm not trying to
aggravate you; it's just this
doesn't exactly have an
above-the-board feeling about it.
- What's going on?
- Barbara and Nygma have Tetch.
- They're ransoming the city.
- So what does that have to do with me?
You're handing me over to him.
You can't. You can't.
You cannot do this.
It's a small price to pay
for saving the city.
Yeah, for you.
For me, it's a very large price!
Look, he cannot be trusted.
You're risking everything based
on the word of a sociopath.
Yeah, yeah. Get in the car.
What? It's gonna be fine.
Yeah, Penguin, Nygma, Tetch
all in the same place
for a high-stakes hostage swap.
What could possibly go wrong?
Do you mind?
Look, if I'm gonna be the
city's sacrificial lamb,
the least you could do is
lead me to the slaughter
with a little dignity.
No.
You don't think that I can cause
you trouble once we're inside?
You do, and I'll kill you.
No, you won't.
Not before you have Tetch.
Not before the exchange goes smoothly.
And after that,
what do you care what happens?
Let's just get this over with.
- Thank you.
- Shut up.
My three favorite men.
Don't feel bad, Oswald.
Your death at my hands
was inevitable.
Is that what you
told yourself last time?
I'm assuming the grenade's
not a fashion statement.
Precaution.
You three try anything, I pull the pin.
Kaboom!
No more Tetch.
No hope for an antidote.
- Little crude, don't you think?
- Enough! Let's get this done.
You're infected.
How wonderful.
Nygma!
Did you really think
you could get away with this?
I knew you'd figure out that this was
about Oswald, but how'd you
figure out where we are?
Please. You know how many cops
I got on the payroll?
Oh, baby, you might want to use
your inside growl whilst making
secret calls inside the GCPD.
Now hand him over.
Go!
Let him go! Let him go!
We need to get Tetch!
Now!
That little bastard!
Coming through.
Move out of the way. Rita, move.
All right, let's have a look.
Whoa. What did you do to cauterize this?
I don't, I don't know.
Is he going to be okay?
We'll do everything we can.
What's your relationship to the patient?
Doctor, BP's falling.
We're family.
All right, let's get him
tight, cross-set and prepped for OR.
It looks pretty good.
I'll call the station.
Grab Tetch!
Split up.
Jim.
You and the ex are infected, huh?
I've heard Lee wants to remove
my pretty little head
from my body.
Is it weird that kind of
makes me like her?
You thinking about ripping
anyone's head off, Jim?
I bet you are.
You're so close.
The next time you give in,
the virus will have you.
Stop talking.
Jim!
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
Hey.
There's no back door, no loading
dock, no way this ends well.
The virus will give you
all the strength you need.
It's the only option.
Give in to the darkness.
I said...
- Killer.
- stop talking.
You want to kill me, that I can see,
but without my blood,
no antidote will there be.
- Fight it, Jim.
- I don't know if I can.
He's right. We need him.
Yeah, but not all of him.
Where are they?!
What happened?!
What'd he do?
Oh, Jim.
You sick bastard.
Where's the lab tech?
Where's the lab tech?!
Come on, come on. Here, here.
What?
You've never seen a mason jar
filled with blood before? Go!
Back to work.
You okay?
Oh. Oh.
He's awake.
I was getting lonely.
Where are we?
Oh, we ran into a police blockade.
Had to hunker down a minute.
Where are you taking me?
I don't know.
I'm sort of improvising here.
Why? You have someplace you have to be?
Does it matter?
I imagine you're planning on
dragging this out.
There are so few moments
of pure joy in one's life,
I feel compelled to savor this one.
You mean gloat?
Yes, I do.
It was always one of your least
attractive qualities, Oswald.
It's killing you, isn't it?
What?
To know that you are not
as smart as you think you are.
All of that planning to drive me crazy,
strip me of everything I had,
revealing yourself with a "ta-da,"
and shooting me by the river.
That plan was perfect...
and you know it.
You failed.
I am still alive,
and you are handcuffed in the backseat.
And now you will never be able
to correct your mistake.
I guess not.
Now that they have Tetch's blood,
they can make the antidote;
and after what we tried to pull,
the whole city's
gonna be gunning for us.
Hell, I'm surprised the cops
haven't busted down our door already.
Relax. They've got better things to do.
What are we supposed to do now?
We split up, go to the
safe house, and regroup.
Regroup? For what?!
For whatever the hell I tell you to do!
I'm not waiting anymore.
She's broken every promise
she's ever made to you...
- to us.
- I know.
Safe house is a perfect place to do it.
Okay.
I'll take care of everything.
No.
We do it together.
Yeah.
Whew.
Kowalski and Burrows
are gonna be pissed.
Uh, Tetch's blood is good.
The lab guys are starting work
on an antidote as we speak.
I need to get to Lee. How long?
- How long before it's ready?
- They said we could head there now.
- Where is it?
- Detective Gordon, just in time.
If you'll take a seat
and roll up your sleeve.
We have a dose ready for you right now.
The others will be ready shortly.
I need two.
Sorry. We could only make one of
these single shots so quickly.
No. Two.
All of Tetch's blood
is in the centrifuge machines.
- The process can't be interrupted.
- You're a killer.
It's just one or two hours, max.
You can still catch Lee
before she leaves.
There's not enough time.
Jim.
- Killer!
- Jim. Don't make me... Jim!
No, Jim! Jim!
Damn it! Someone call the bullpen!
Bruce.
I heard about Alfred.
Is he gonna be okay?
Go home, Selina.
What happened?
No.
- No, you don't get to do this.
- Do what?
Walk back into my life.
You think I need your pity? I don't.
- That's not why I'm here.
- You want to know what happened?!
- You wouldn't understand.
- Why?
Because I'm-I'm not desperate
to believe in something?
Because you don't believe in
anyone or anything but yourself.
It's called surviving.
And unlike you,
I know who I am.
I don't need anyone to tell me.
What are you even doing here, Selina?
You don't give a damn about Alfred,
and you sure as hell
don't care about me.
I know you better than that.
Yeah.
I thought you did.
Have a nice life.
Lee?
I don't like to be kept waiting.
You're still fighting it.
I can help you with that.
We both know that's not what I want.
I want you.
I want you and all your darkness.
Give in.
Give in to your darkness.
Be free.
Don't you get tired of making
the same mistake over and over?
You think I'm making a mistake?
Instead of killing me
when you had the chance,
you've decided to feed your ego.
You want to talk ego? Riddler?
You will always fail, Oswald.
Because you will always let
your base emotions drive you.
Hate,
anger, fear,
- love.
- Shut up.
You want to know why I could never
- love someone like you, Oswald?
- I'm warning you.
Because you are a spoiled child
who throws a tantrum
any time he doesn't get what he wants!
Especially when what he wants
doesn't want him back.
You're right. I shouldn't have waited.
But, unlike you, I am in the position
to rectify my mistake.
Prepare for one massive tantrum.
No!
That is not possible!
It is my turn!
It is my turn to kill you!
Like I said...
...you will always fail!
Because you'll never change.
Maybe.
But at least I know who I am.
That day, by the edge of the river,
that was the moment you were reborn.
And that was a lie!
You're entire persona is based
on a lie!
And there is nothing
you can do to change that!
Actually...
maybe there is.
Attention.
All travelers must pass through
security checkpoints
before boarding the train.
Please report anyone who might
be displaying signs of infection
to the nearest checkpoint
or security officer
so that immediate medical assistance...
Hey, this isn't a public entrance.
Oh, crap.
Police! Move it! Police!
Move aside! Police!
Move, move! Get out of my way!
He's trying to stop us.
You can't let him.
I'll see you on the train.
Police! Police! Move!
Out of the way! Move! Jim!
Jim!
Now we're gonna be delayed, aren't we?
You gonna shoot me, Harvey?
This isn't you!
It is.
Please don't make me do this.
Lee and I belong together.
I know.
I know how bad you want that,
to forget about everything
that happened, but you can't.
It's not real.
This is who I am!
- This is who I've always been.
- No, it's not!
Who you are is a choice.
It always has been. It still is.
This is who you are.
You're the best cop I ever worked with.
The best friend I've ever had.
If you love Lee,
go save her.
Tickets.
To our great adventure.
I love you, Lee.
No.
What have you done?
Really?
A hacksaw?
Even your disposal tactics are idiotic.
Guess I'm just old-fashioned.
Did you really think I
wouldn't figure it out?
The two of you have been whispering
like teenagers for weeks.
Oh, Butchie.
You shouldn't have waited.
Well, believe me,
if it weren't for Tabby,
you'd have been dead a long time ago.
You're trying to tell me
she had nothing to do with this?
- That's right.
- Oh, so you've just
gone behind her back, have you?
I was gonna hit you
before we got to the safe house.
Play dumb when you didn't show.
Leaning into your strengths?
You want to know why you're
always taking shots at me?
The giant size of the target?
It's because for all your tough talk,
you miss her.
You miss her loyalty, her strength.
She made you better, and you know it.
And you sacrificed that, for what?
Play queen for a day?
Pathetic.
If it helps...
...you never deserved her
in the first...
I guess we'll see.
I-I don't know if you can hear me.
But if you can,
Alfred, you need to fight.
I don't know what I would do
without you.
Alfred, please.
Please don't leave me.
Here we are.
Again.
Wow.
I have to tell you,
this feels really great.
Glad I could help.
Any last words?
I'm fine for now.
I beg your pardon?
I'll wait.
I'm going to kill you, Oswald.
There is no later.
If you have something to say...
now is the time.
Duly noted.
Oh, whatever.
I'm not letting you ruin this for me.
You don't have anything to say,
but I do.
Good-bye, Oswald.
I removed the bullets
when you were knocked out.
Right before I called them.
In the backseat,
the pin I used to unlock my cuffs?
My tiepin.
I thought it should be personal.
You were just trying to make me
think I had the upper hand.
It all fell into place.
How did you know that Barbara
would show up at the warehouse?
I didn't.
If it wasn't for her,
Gordon would have turned me over,
and I'd most likely be dead.
But fortune favors the bold.
You said you called them
after you knocked me out.
You knew that I'd bring you here.
I know you, Ed.
I may be driven by my emotions,
but you are driven by something
much more predictable:
a desperate, compulsive need
to complete what you've started
in exacting fashion.
Why didn't you just kill me, Oswald?
You were the one time
I let love weaken me,
and I want you around
as a constant reminder
to never make that mistake again.
No...
Barbara?
Butch?
Was killing Nygma... really
that important to you?
Did you kill Butch?
He said you didn't have anything to do
with him trying to kill me.
Is that true?
What does it matter?
All right, for argument's sake,
let's say I haven't
been the best friend.
Do you think we could put this behind us
and move forward?
Did you kill Butch?
That doesn't sound like a "yes."
I need to know.
It's the only way
we'll be able to move forward.
Yes.
I killed him.
But it's not like you gave me a choice!
There's always a choice.
How many times have I
told you not to bring
a whip to a gunfight?
Now we can move forward.
The Tetch antidote has been released
over the city with a 90% cure rate,
with individual antidotes
now being manufactured
and given to GCPD officers...
You're awake!
I'm sorry, Alfred.
It wasn't your fault, was it?
I completely lost my way.
I've been trying to find
who I am for so long,
searching for some greater meaning.
I don't know who I am, Alfred.
Who am I supposed to be?
I can't help you with that one, mate.
You're a man now.
You got to find your own path.
I'm not like you.
You've always been
so sure of who you are.
Oh, I don't know about that.
I've been through some very dark places,
as have you.
You need to find your true north
and let that guide you.
What's yours?
You.
It's always been you.
You got to find something
that you really care about...
and you protect it at all costs.
And when you find it...
...you'll never be lost again.
And while the arrival of an antidote
is certainly welcome news,
the death and the destruction
the virus left in its wake
will no doubt reverberate through
the city for years to come.
Yeah?
Is Barbara around?
No.
And she's not coming back.
What do you want?
I'm not sure.
I just know I'm tired of
just surviving.
I want more.
I want to move up.
Figured this was a good place to start.
I'm at a bit of a crossroads myself.
You hungry?
You buying?
Give it a whirl.
That is the logo for my new club.
What are we gonna call it?
The Iceberg Lounge.
Clever. 'Cause you're
nicknamed Penguin, right?
There's that.
And then...
there's the club's
centerpiece attraction.
Lee?
Jim...
I knew if I saw you, I might
not have the courage to leave.
And I need to.
I finally understand Gotham
in a way I suspect you always have.
It's a place where the strongest
and most cunning rule...
...where the cost of survival
is paid for by others...
...and everyone feels alone.
Having the virus showed me
the city as it truly was.
As I truly was.
In so many ways,
the virus made me feel reborn.
He's a gangster; probably
got what he deserved.
- He is?
- Sure. That's Butch Gilzean.
Really? His chart lists
his birth name as Cyrus Gold.
Cyrus Gold?
He must have changed it at some point.
But if having the virus
allowed Gotham to embrace
its worst self,
the cure should remind us
there is always hope.
A chance to remember who we can be
rather than who we are.
I don't know if Gotham deserves saving,
but I do know one thing.
If anyone can save it...
it's you.
And in return, I believe
it can save you as well.
And then maybe one day,
it will send you back to me.
Until then,
love always...
Lee.
Can I come in, Captain?
No.
You threw me against a train car.
- I know.
- Two... actually.
I felt like a freaking cartoon.
I am really sorry about that.
You see Lee?
She's gone.
She left Gotham.
You okay?
I will be.
- You want to get a drink?
- It's noon.
I didn't ask you what time it was.
I asked if you wanted to get a drink.
Sure.
I'm good.
Any word on Tetch?
Yeah, he stumbled into some hospital.
They patched him up,
shipped him back to Arkham.
You know, I'd actually like to
get back to being a detective.
Do some good old-fashioned police work.
The kind that doesn't involve
secret cults or blood viruses.
- Do we have anything like that?
- Not really.
Half the force is coming off
24-hour shifts,
but we could, uh... hit the streets
like a couple of old beat cops,
see if we could stir up
some trouble, huh?
I don't know, seems kind of beneath me.
You know, seeing as I'm the...
best cop you've
ever worked with and all.
Oh, oh, I was just telling you
whatever crap came to mind
so you wouldn't punch a hole
through my head.
Uh-huh.
Like a hostage negotiation,
you just tell someone
- what they want to hear.
- Sure, sure.
If you didn't have the virus,
- I would've kicked your butt.
- Is that right?
Yeah, absolutely.
It was so good.
That was such a good dinner.
I never ever had sushi like that.
It was great, whatever it was.
Money!
- Now!
- Dad?
- It's-it's okay, sweetheart.
- Now!
No!
- Dad!
- No!
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net